<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">CharDhamYatra</string>
    <string name="name1">CharDham<b>Yatra</b></string>

    //Kedarnath attractions
    <string name="sonprayag">The mesmerisingly beautiful settlement of Sonprayag is located around 20 km away on the route to Kedarnath. Situated at the confluence of two sacred rivers, Basuki and Mandakini, Sonprayag offers a scintillating view of snow covered mountains and the lush green Sonprayag valley.</string>
    <string name="chorbari">The mighty Chorbari (Chorabari) Bamak Glacier, the origin of River Mandakini, is located about 2 km upstream from Kedarnath, with a trail leading from the Kedarnath temple to the glacier snout. Several hanging glaciers and avalanche chutes feed the 6-km-long glacier located at about 3,820 m. It is a popular trekking trail.</string>
    <string name="mount_kedarnath">Mount Kedarnath or the Kedarnath peak, also called Kedarnath Main by mountaineers, is the imposing mountain that is visible behind the Kedarnath temple. Considered auspicious by pilgrims, the snow-draped peak at an altitude of around 6,940 m is a challenging climb for professionals from across the world. The Kedarnath peak and the Kedarnath Dome are part of the Gangotri group of peaks in the western Garhwal Himalayas. Kedarnath is the highest peak on the south side of the Gangotri glacier, and Kedarnath Dome is the third highest.</string>
    <string name="kedar_dome">Kedar Dome is a majestic, dome-shaped peak standing at a height of 6,831 m within the folds of the Garhwal Himalayas. Named after Lord Shiva, the mountain forms the backdrop to the Kedarnath temple. It attracts mountaineers from across the world, who mostly attempt climbing from its northwestern flank. The peak is also ideal for ski ascents and is popular among professional skiers. The trek to Kedar Dome is easy but requires high altitude trekking experience. It offers great views of the Gangotri glacier, Gangotri peaks, and the stunning Mount Kedarnath.</string>
    <string name="kedar_wildlife">The lush Kedarnath Wildlife Sanctuary, bordered by Kedarnath and Chaukhamba peaks, is home to the rare Himalayan musk deer, a reason why its also known as the Kedarnath Musk Deer Sanctuary. Spread over approximately 975 sq km, the sanctuary has a large number of temples located within its precincts, the Kedarnath temple being the most popular.</string>
    <string name="adi_shankaracharya">One of the most popular attractions in Kedarnath, the Adi Shankaracharya Samadhi is believed to be the place where sage Adi Shankaracharya attained Moksha (freedom from physical body). It is located just behind Kedarnath temple. A hot water spring nearby is believed to have the cure to all human sufferings.</string>
    <string name="sumeru">A 6,350-m-high mountain in the Gangotri region, it is the closest neighbour of Kedar Dome. This mountain is encircled by several peaks and the trekking route passes through crystal clear lakes, glacier moraines, ice sheets and snow-capped mountains.</string>
    <string name="mayali_pass">Situated at an elevation of 5,300 m, this pass is just 15 km from Kedarnath. The moderately challenging trek to this pass offers spectacular views of Masar Tal and Vasuki Tal along with Thalay Sagar, Kedar dome and other peaks of the Gangotri region.</string>
    <string name="vasuki">At a distance of 8 km from Kedarnath, this beautiful lake is situated at an altitude of 4,135 m. Set in the midst of snowy mountains this lake provides a charming view of the massive Chaukhamba peaks. The trek to the lake passes through the Chaturangi and Vasuki glaciers. Locals say the lake draws its name from its shape, which resembles serpent king Vasuki wrapped around Lord Shivas neck.</string>
    <string name="gandhi_sarovar">The Chorabari Lake or the Gandhi Sarovar, a permanent waterbody on the side of the glacier, is where some of Mahatma Gandhis ashes were immersed in 1948. The small lake with crystal clear water is situated at the mouth of the Chorbari Bamak glacier and is at the foot of the Kedarnath and Kirthi Stambh peaks. The grassy landscape and beautiful Madhu Ganga waterfall en route to this lake make the trek memorable. The best time to get the most scintillating view is during morning as the weather of this place changes abruptly.</string>
    <string name="gaurikund">This sacred hot water spring is considered to be one of the holiest sites for Hindu devotees, who take a dip in it to “wash away sins”. Nestled amidst snow-capped peaks and panoramic views of the Himalayas, Gaurikund is the starting point of the 16-km trek to the Kedarnath shrine. Devotees believe that this was the site where Goddess Parvati, Lord Shivas divine consort, had meditated to win Lord Shiva as her husband. A temple dedicated to the goddess is also located here.</string>

</resources>